

Resume
Full Stack Developer | Software
Developer

## Personal details

**George Ochieng' Outa** 



george.jarviz@gmail.com



+254 (0) 700 613065



1845 40100 Kisumu



outafrica.me



linkedin.com/in/george-outa



github.com/outafrica

### Skills

**Test Driven** 

PHPUnit/Pest)

**Problem Solver** 

**Development (TDD** 

| Agile Methodologies               | ••••• |
|-----------------------------------|-------|
| Laravel(PHP)                      | ••••  |
| VueJs                             | ••••  |
| Tailwind                          | ••••  |
| Flutter                           | ••••  |
| API integrations                  | ••••  |
| MySQL/PostgresSQL/MongoDB/MariaDB | ••••  |

## **Career Profile**

As a highly skilled and successful leader with seven years comprehensive experience in software development principles, I possess a wide range of knowledge and skills that allow me to contribute toward the success of projects I undertake. Throughout my career, I have been acknowledged as a solution-focused professional with the ability to design and develop innovative applications using advanced technologies. I have advanced proficiencies in Laravel(PHP), VueJs, Flutter, and excellent customer service skills. I also have a solid foundation in MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Node.JS. My attention to detail, organizational skills and strong communication have allowed me to lead software development teams and ensure the success of each project assigned to me.

# **Employment**

Feb 2022 - Sep 2022

#### **Full Stack Developer**

International Development Law Organization, Nairobi

Worked as a consultant for the Judiciary of Kenya through the International Development Law Organization (IDLO).

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Collect user requirements based on newly realized features from emerging problems.
- Implement new features in applications based on gathered requirements after object-oriented analysis.
- Analyze issues and make improvements to the project's existing features and components.
- Coordinate with other team members for development of portal solutions to support API.
- Develop technical documentation in coordination with software engineering teams.
- Complete all the duties efficiently & timely as issued by the team lead.

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

#### Lead Mobile(Flutter) Developer

:Brij Innovation Group, Nairobi

A modern, simple and secure way to make instant payments, send and receive money, pay bills, and shop across Africa.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Implement UI and UXs from design team.
- Implement unit, widget & integration tests using Mockito.
- Perform code reviews and mentor my team by providing support where needed
- Publish apps on Android Playstore, and IOS Appstore/TestFlight.

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

#### **Full Stack Developer**

International Development Law Organization, Nairobi

Worked as a consultant for the Judiciary of Kenya through the International Development Law Organization (IDLO).

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Gather user requirements based on new features realized from arising issues.
- Develop new features based on gathered

| Communicator                 | •••• |
|------------------------------|------|
| Team Player                  | •••• |
| GIT                          | •••• |
| CI/CD                        | •••• |
| DevOps<br>(DigitalOcean/AWS) | •••• |
| JIRA                         | •••• |
| Sentry                       | •••• |
| C++                          | •••• |
| Languages —                  |      |
| English                      | •••• |
| Kiswahli                     | •••• |
| Hobbies —                    |      |

Chess

Basketball

Cooking

Reading novels

requirements and provide improvements on existing code components and features of applications.

- Implement methods for identifying and resolving technical issues.
- Provide code documentation and other application inputs to technical documents.

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

#### **Full Stack Developer**

#### Enzihealth Limited, Nairobi

A health focused ecosystem that allow users to get medical attention at the comfort of their spaces even from work place, home and outdoors.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Implement APIs to support registration and hail applications using Africa's talking via USSD.
- Implement <u>Safaricom Mpesa APIs</u> to handle payment requests.
- Perform unit tests to validate application components and debug code based on unit tests results.
- Develop a mobile version of the app using flutter to enable registration, hailing requests and payment processing.
- Deploy project to production.

Oct 2017 - Oct 2021

### **Full Stack Developer**

Uhired Limited, Nairobi

A job marketing and recruitment service provider.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Implement and write tests for new and existing features.
- Provide technical support to the team members and handle client issues as they arise.
- Upgrade the project from Laravel 4.2 to Laravel 7.0
- Maintain the project by fixing bugs & documenting code.
- Deploy project to production.

# **Education**

May 2013 - Sep 2018

#### **Bachelor of Science - Computer Science**

University of Nairobi, Nairobi

Graduated from University of Nairobi - Nairobi,

Kenya

BSc. Computer Science.

Cluster; Upper Second-Class Honors

Feb 2008 - Nov 2011

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE) O-level

Maranda Boys High School, Bondo

## References

Mr. Leonard Korir - Lead Technology Manager

Brij Innovation Group, Nairobi

+254 728 355429, lkorir@bridgeinnovation.io

Mr. Steven Ikileng - A/g. ICT Director

Judiciary of Kenya, Nairobi

+254 722 980 453, steven.ikileng@court.go.ke

Mrs. Grace Nyagaya - Systems Administrator KEMRI/CDC at CGHR, Kisumu +254 722 941 721, gnyagaya@kemricdc.org